Melissa McFadzien

mmcf647@aucklanduni.ac.nz linkedin.com/in/melissa-mcfadzien pickles-and-olives-online.onrender.com 021 179 8602

Summary

Current Master of Information Technology student at the University of Auckland.

The challenges and problem-solving opportunities presented by the Covid-19 pandemic sparked my interest in techbased solutions and coding, leading me to discover my passion in this field. I have since honed my technical skills in both front-end and back-end development, and I am excited to further expand my expertise within the industry.

My undergraduate education in Communication Design and practical experience in the e-commerce sector have been invaluable to my current studies. They have equipped me with skills in design thinking and user-centered business models, providing me with a unique perspective on developing tech solutions, which I am excited to put into practice.

Skills

- Java HTML
- JavaScript CSS
- React JS SQL Git
- Vue JS

- UX / UI Design
- Adobe Creative Suite (Ps, Id, Ai)
- Creative problem solving
- Peer tutoring

Honours and Awards

- Elected Student Representative on the Auckland ICT Graduate School Board of Studies 2023
- First in Course Award in Advanced Information Security Semester Two, 2022
- Certificate of Outstanding Achievement in Programming with Web Technologies Semester One, 2022
- Code Like a Girl Scholarship Recipient 2021

Experience

The University of Auckland Auckland, NZ

2022 - present

Graduate Teaching Assistant October 2022 - present

Tutoring students in the Post Graduate Certificate of Information Technology. Responsibilities include providing support during lab exercises for Java programming and web development (HTML, CSS, and JavaScript), monitoring group project progress and doing live demonstrations of solutions for class and lab activities.

Pagani Clothing Ltd. Auckland, NZ

2018 - 2021

Digital Content Producer June 2020 - August 2021

Producing and managing all digital and visual content, including design and production of digital communications, website asset and product management, and directing / photographing product and campaign imagery.

Digital Marketing Assistant March 2019 - June 2020

Assisting in all areas of the marketing and web store teams. Responsibilities included website maintenance, budget and sales reporting, third-party marketing correspondence, and office culture coordination.

Pagani Cont.

Product Survey and Web Dispatch Support November 2018 - March 2019

Creating, sending, and reporting daily product response surveys used for purchasing and budgeting. During this time, I also supported the web dispatch team, picking and packing orders.

Bird Brooklyn Brooklyn, NY

2018

Back of House Operations Coordinator May 2018 - October 2018

Responsibilities included multi-store stock management and transfers, international vendor communications and special-order management.

Sales Associate January 2018 - May 2018

Snowe Home New York, NY

2017

Sales Associate and Brand Ambassador October - December 2017

Overland Footwear Ltd. Auckland, NZ

2016 - 2017

Keyholder (Mi Piaci) November 2016 - October 2017

Photography and Design Intern August 2016 - October 2016

Education

Master's Degree Information Technology The University of Auckland **Graduating 2023**

Bachelor's Degree

2016

Communication Design (Formerly Graphic Design) Auckland University of Technology

- Major in Illustration and Photography
- Minor in Creative Entrepreneurship

Other

- Programming with C# Code Like a Girl
- Responsive Web Design freeCodeCamp

References available upon request.